/*
Programming languages abstract what machines do

To understand how exactly...

What are you allowed to say?
What are the semantics of the various language constructs?
What effect does various language constructs have on the performance?
How do you decompose a larger program into smaller ones? How do you achieve code reuse?
Who decides how values are organized in memory? Who decides when storage is allocated or deallocated?
How do you interact with devices other than the processor and memory?

C++
-Greater control over issues affecting performance
-Write programs as low-level as those interacting directly with hardware and software
-Target any variety of platforms while maintaining a high standard performance

Von Neumann architecture
CPU - central processing unit controls execution of programs
Programs are made of instructions, each specifing CPU actions
Instructions and data are stored in main memory, a giant array of bytes, each cell having an address often counted in bytes and often starting from 0
Instructions can modify instructions and data stored in main memory, allowing self-modifying or automatically generating programs

Near the CPU is collection of registers
This provides fast access to much fewer than 100 values, 32 or 64 bytes each (far faster than main memory access)


Instruction pointer (a register) - keeps track of address in main memory where the next instruction to be executed resides; as instructions are executed, the pointer is updated accordingly

Von Neumann Cycle
Read instruction from memory
Decode instruction (decide what it's supposed to do, and what data is needed)
Read operands if it's an ADD instruction, go find the two values that need to be added)
Execute the instruction, by performing the appropriate operation on the operands
Store any results, if needed (into registers or main memory)

program running on a Von Neumann machine is a sequence of instructions that perform gradual modification on a collection of memory
*/

/*
C++ compiler 
1. verify syntax and semantics, static checking
2. produce machine instructions with the same observable effect as program (optimization is possible)

types specify how much memory and which operations (CPU instructions) are appropriate

no control structures - execution based on order of storage in memory (default)
conditionals - largely CPU's jump and branch instructions (influenced if: 0 being false, everything else true)
loops work similarily to conditionals, same influence


functions
calling conventions - define how two functions collaborate with each other; must be same for both functions

Where will the callee find arguments passed from the caller?
Where will the caller find return value when the callee returns?
When the callee is finished, how does it know how to jump back to precisely where the caller left off?
Who ensures that the registers — which could've been used the caller to store temporary results of calculations in progress — are put back when the callee is finished, so the caller can continue in the same state it was in previously?




whenever a function returns, it returns to the function that was called most recently

if a() calls b(), and b calls c() 
c() -> b() -> a()

run-time stack
stored in main memory
store activation records, one for each function that is currently active
when function is called, info is put on, such that the most recent called function is on the top at any time;
when functions return, their information is popped, revealing information about functions that called them, 

stack pointer - stores top address of run-time stack


activation record

temporary #n
← stack pointer
local variable #n
saved registers
← frame pointer
return pointer
return value
argument #n


caller passes arguments to callee 
return value - run-time stack stores makes room for return value
return pointer - instruction that executes after callee finishes
saved registers 
  caller knows which to protect
  callee knows which to use,
  any used by both need to be saved before call, so values can be restored when we return
local varaiables - variables declared within function
temporaries - temporary values of calculations (better to store in registries, but most likely will end up on run-time stack temporarily)
stack pointer - points to top of activation record, so new data can be pushed and popped, but we always know where the top is
frame pointer - enusres everything is at a known distance from frame pointer, as amount temporaries may change and number of parameters in each call differ

TLDR:
 caller pushes some things on the run-time stack (the arguments, the return pointer, some saved registers)
 callee push others (other saved registers, local variables)
 While callee runs, temporaries might be pushed and/or popped. 
 When the callee ends, the process is unwound (i.e., the things pushed previously are now popped).

 Basically writing short functions is costly on memory...
*/

/*
Memory Hierarchy
data needed more often is closer to CPU
data not as needed is farther

registers > cache > main memory > disks > networks 
high speed <-                         ->high memory
this helps us decide where data should be stored, and the order in which data is accessed

cache stores values recently accessed
data is stored in blocks instead of bytes 

algorithms with sequential access superior to ones with equivalent number of data accesses farther apart...

locality of reference - accessing locations in memory that are very near locations recently accessed

Making best use of available hardware
Instructions only used certain parts of the CPU
Most of the CPU would lay dormant
CPUs can execute multiple instructions, assuming that they don't share parts

pipelining, where a processor can be in different stages of executing different instructions simultaneously

can stall, because some instructions can't begin until the instructions immediately preceding them have finished
branch instructions make it unclear which instruction is next (combatted by branch prediction: reasonable guesses or heuristics--if wrong, stop and go back; more costly)
out-of-order execution- execute in a different order than written

*/
