/*
all parameters in C++ are pass-by-value by default
values of arguments specified by caller passed into function
function only has access to copies


activation record is stored on the run-time stack whenever a function is called, and that function's parameters is stored in that activation record. 

Pass-by-value parameters have their values copied into activation record during the call. 

Wherever the function needs to access parameters, the compiler emits code that finds their values in the activation record

1. pass-by-value parameters allow corresponding arguments to be either lvalues or rvalues
2. cost because of copying parameter values into the activation record
3. value of variable passed into function is guaranteed to never change
*/

/*
references - alternate name for value; "refers" to value 
declared by adding an & to its type

int& - reference (&) to an integer

1. must be initialized explicitly when defined, so they refer to something of an appopriate type
2. once initialized, it cannot refer to anything else
3. can only reference lvalues

references can be used as if they are the original value

#include <iostream>
int main() {
  int i = 1;
  std::cout << i << std::endl << std::endl;

  int& r = i;
  std::cout << i << std::endl;
  std::cout << r << std::endl << std::endl;

  r = 2;
  std::cout << i << std::endl;
  std::cout << r << std::endl << std::endl;

  r = 1;
  i = 2;

  std::cout << i << std::endl;
  std::cout << r << std::endl << std::endl;
  
  return 0;
}
*/



/*
pass-by-reference
1. These parameters enable functions to alter the arguments passed to them.
2. Avoids the cost of making copies of the arguments. For parameters of types whose values are inexpensive to copy, this is no win (and possibly even a loss), but for parameters that are potentially expensive to copy (like strings or complex data structures), this can be a massive performance benefit. Temporary loss of the protection of our original values...
3. References must refer to lvalues.

#include <iostream>
void swap(int& a, int& b) {
    int temp = a;
    a = b;
    b = temp;
}

int main() {
  int x = 5;
  int y = 6;

  swap(x,y);

  std::cout << x << std::endl;
  std::cout << y << std::endl;

  return 0;
}
*/

/*
assigning values into variables, types must be compatible

types can be same
C++ freely (and implicityly) converts if there is a known conversion--information loss may happen

Pass-by-value parameter 
as long as the corresponding argument is a compatible type,it will be legal to pass it.

Pass-by-reference parameter, the types actually have to match. Because the reference is referring to the actual location in memory, it's important that this location is treated identically, otherwise assigning to it might give a radically different result than expected.

*/

/*
two functions can have the same name in the same scope, their parameter types and/or return types have to be distinguishable 

if compiler isn't sure what to convert a value to

Exact matches are always taken first. If there's a version of a function that takes precisely the same types of parameters as the types of arguments being passed, that version wins.
Matches involving onverting from a type with a smaller size to a type with one that's at least as large. (e.g., int → long, int → double, float → double) are taken next. 

Matches involving other standard conversions (e.g., double → int, float → char) are taken next.
*/

/*
default arguments, so parameters that have common values can be substituted by defaults if they're not specified in calls to the function

double vectorLength(double x, double y, double z = 0.0)
{
    return std::sqrt(x * x + y * y + z * z);
}

parameters with default arguments must be listed at the end of the parameter list. There can be as many defaults as you want, since C++ matches arguments to parameters in the order specified — the compiler would never know which parameters you meant to pass unless only the last one or more could be missing.
*/